[Cheetu] Well, well. I guess
you guys were lying in wait for me.
Sorry, but that's gonna backfire on you.
You're gonna die without
ever getting the chance to strike back.
-[Knuckle laughs] Oh, yeah?
-Hmm?
I barely felt a thing.
With a punch like that,
you could hit us a few thousand times more
and still not kill us.
[laughs]
Okay, I get it.
You're just trying to act tough.
[growls]
[laughs] The strike's already been called,
and you're still swinging. [laughs]
Just a warning. I've been holding back.
I can run faster and punch harder.
He actually aimed accurately at my face.
[Cheetu] Huh? Him, too?
He's tracking where I'm going to be
before he attacks.
I've only just encountered them,
and they've adjusted to my speed
that quickly?
They're nothing like the guys
from yesterday.
How fun! Makes it worthwhile
playing with your food.
[grunting]
[groaning]
[opening theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
GRUDGE X AND X DREAD
[Knuckle and Morel groaning]
[Cheetu laughs]
Minds quicker than your bodies?
You obviously can't compete physically,
so how are you gonna compensate?
[chuckles]
With our wits and experience.
[exhales]
Huh?
[laughs]
Does that mean
that you're not running away, then?
So it's a smoke screen.
They'll use it as cover for their attack.
Well, let's see what they've got.
Here it comes.
[gasps]
When you're startled,
your whole body freezes up.
but even so, I'm perfectly fine.
Huh?
What the hell is this?
Well, it looks like your anger
is binding you to your surroundings,
[growls]
Shut up!
They're gone.
Where did you go?
[A.P.R.] It is time.
You have accrued interest.
[growls]
[scoffs] It doesn't matter
what your power does.
I just have to leave you in my dust.
[Morel] It looks like
he's powerless against Zetsu.
We'll just chase him down,
box him in, and that'll be the end of it.
But doesn't your ability lose its effect
if the target moves too far away?
Well, sure, it'll stop accruing interest,
but it won't disappear.
Best part is, we won't even
need to change it to IRS.
We've already seen what he can do.
You damn fool!
Just because we know his pitches
Yeah, you're right.
Damn. I can't shake this stupid thing.
it must be Nen.
I'm gonna need a lot more
than just speed here.
[soft crackling]
[crackling continues]
[Shoot] Kite is inside this cage,
but he's no longer
the person you once knew.
It's okay.
We're gonna find a way
to cure him somehow.
[Shoot] Hotel Rafflesia.
Once I deal a certain amount of damage
to my enemy,
the cage traps them inside,
-either whole or just a part.
-[gasps]
[Killua] So that's how he took my eye.
[gasps]
Be careful.
He can't use Nen,
but he's still as strong as ever.
[breath shaking]
[Gon] Kite.
He mechanically attacks anything
that gets close to him.
[gasps]
You haven't hit me since…
since the day we first met.
[growls]
Well? Are you gonna let this continue?
Gon can't defend himself
with Nen either, right?
It'll be fine.
Gon is bound to notice.
In fact, he might have
figured it out already,
if we're lucky.
[Knov] Perhaps…
he's suppressing his reflexes
to dodge or block,
but Gon shouldn't be able to adapt
so quickly in his condition.
[Killua] He just doesn't know
what else to do. I'm sure of it.
[blows landing]
[Gon] He'll go right next.
His punches hurt more than this,
a lot more!
[both gasp]
You can leave everything to us.
[gasps]
Gon can't see that thing, but it activates
whenever someone touches Kite.
You're gonna need some seriously advanced
fighting skills to defeat him now.
My ability sealed Kite's Nen,
but that thing right there
I'm sorry. We had no other choice.
If you keep away, he won't attack.
[breath trembling]
I'll fix you. I promise.
[door closes]
Killua…
I could tell that something was different.
What did you two do?
You changed so much in such a short time.
We didn't do anything.
They're the ones who changed us.
A FEW WEEKS LATER
[Morel] So what do you think?
Was it right to let them tag along?
We'll be breaking our promise
to the old man, you know.
It's not a problem.
The test was only intended to determine
who would and would not enter the NGL.
And we are, at the moment,
headed to the Republic of East Gorteau.
Isn't that correct?
Sure sounds like
you're splitting hairs to me.
You're not suggesting
we take them back, are you?
[Morel] No.
Those two are full-grown tigers now,
and the best thing about full-grown tigers
is they can take care of themselves.
Well, Killua is capable.
Do you think Gon is too?
I must admit I was impressed
by the way he moved back there,
but I can't say
I've seen him show any fire since then.
He's improved with training,
but he clearly lacks any real focus.
He's inconsistent.
His power levels can vary widely.
Maybe so, but at least
he's consistently inconsistent.
He doesn't take things too seriously
unless he has to.
I feel his lack of motivation
is like a coiled up spring.
he hates enough to unleash it on.
Well, we'll see soon enough.
Gon's Nen will be back tomorrow,
just in time,
and the enemy's straight ahead.
Diego has personally invited
all the citizens in the country
to the capital city of Peijing
where practically every citizen,
from infants to the infirm,
have all been summoned for a celebration
spanning three whole days.
I believe it's rather safe to assume
that this time around,
But if he announced his successor
and abdication simultaneously,
it would send a very powerful message.
Still, I find it hard to imagine
[announcer] Well, whatever it is,
in ten short days,
the whole world will be watching.
-In other news…
-Colt has a theory.
He believes that the celebration
will be used to sort the population.
but 99% of the humans that are there now
will most certainly die.
But we cannot let that happen.
We have ten days.
The old man, what's he up to right now?
He sent me a text a little while ago
saying he's already infiltrated
East Gorteau.
I haven't heard a word from him
since then.
[Killua] So do you think
he's been taken out?
[Knov] Before he left, he told us
that if we don't hear from him today,
we're to assume the worst has happened.
-[cell phone rings]
-[all gasp]
[Morel] That old man's
got some satellites for ears.
[Netero] I want you
to split into three pairs
and lure the Royal Guards
away from the King.
Start at midnight
the night before the rally.
From the Old Man With Satellite Ears.
That old bastard
scares the crap out of me.
the 30 days are up meow,
and that means
it's time for me to be moving on.
So see you later.
[laughs]
[gasps]
Well, all right.
It looks like you can use Nen again.
Gon, don't hold back.
Show him your Jajanken.
[Gon] A real attack?
Yes, damn it!
Give me everything you've got,
or you're off the team.
[Gon] Got it.
[gasps]
Show me rock!
[breathing heavily]
[breath trembling]
Gon…
that's enough.
[gasps]
Killua! Thanks a lot.
Uh, sorry, Mr. Morel.
I really was just about to kill you.
[gasps]
You got me real good there, kid.
And you've got just about
the right amount of crazy in you too.
Okay, we'll split up now.
Go and fulfill your mission
by any means necessary.
Knov and I will take Shaiapouf.
Best of luck out there.
[narrator] The preparations
for the final battle are complete at last.
[Gon] Next time, "A Lawless Home."
-[Killua] Wanna get controlled?
-[Gon] Huh?
[Killua] Stick this antenna here.
[Gon] Huh? It just has to be Killua.